- [Instructor] With Zustand, accessing
and consuming store data is very simple.
We're going to see how to bind components
to the state, how to read the state, and also,
how to update the state directly from the components.
So to read store data, components simply need
to import the useCounter hook.
So we already exporting this one from here.
Next, we want to import it inside App.js.
That's going to be useCounter like so.
And we simply need to call this one
from inside the components, useCounter.
And that's it.
We're going to have access to the store data
and also the functions to carry over the data
so we can use increment, decrement and also reset
to update the state directly from our component.
And from now on, from line 11 to 15,
we no longer need these lines.
We're going to remove any use of the React API.
I'm going to remove also here the useState.
And we just need now the useCounter
because we're going to be able to manage the states
with this simple hook
that we could call from any components.
So now the app is already up and running.
We're going to try now our app.
We can now successfully access the states right here.
So let's see if this is up and running nicely.
We can increment then decrement and also reset.
The thing that we want to do is to add some control flow.
We want to allow to decrement
only if the value doesn't go below zero.
So we're just going to add an if statement right here.
We're going to check if get count
is less than zero, we're going to return false.
Simple as that. Very simple.
And let's go back, let's just make sure
that this is still up and running.
So now if we refresh,
we're going to try again to increment and then decrement.
So it's not going to decrement if we reach the value of zero.
Excellent.
So now the components are successfully connected
to the store.
Here you see that this is a very simple process
and data flow and Zustand provides an easy access
and update of the states,
which makes it a very friendly alternative
to other state management solutions.